Cover Letter
DM Oberholtzer

With over 25 years in heavy industry, my skills and experience are varied and ex tensive in both the engineering and production scopes of Mining, Mineral process ing and Earth moving machinery.

■Having recently been retrenched from my position as Plant Engineer on a Copper Mine / processing plant in the DRC, I would be immediately available to join and make a positive contribution to any Engineering Department and Operation.

With over 20 years in Heavy Industry Engineering, my experience and skill in coa ching and managing engineering teams, departmental functions and projects is extensive.

As a qualified Fitter and Turner, I obtained my NHD and have risen through the r anks over my career. This makes me a hands on Engineer, drawing from experience and years of knowledge performing and managing engineering tasks / teams / depar tments and projects.

I take ownership and accountability for my plant, am self-motivated, results dri ven and safety conscious.

My key focus is on Safety and legal compliance, Plant / equipment availabilities and efficiencies, Budget control (Opex / Capex) and training / skill developmen t of employees.

Brief history of past roles Apprentice - Fitter and Turner Fitter and Turner - Underground Coal mine Fitter and Turner - Chrome smelting operation

Maintenance specialist - Chrome smelting operation (Obtained my National Higher Diploma in Mechanical Engineering) Shift Coordinator (Production) - Pelletising and Sintering Plant, Chrome ore processing General Forman - Pelletising and Sint ering Plant (Four production teams plus the Engineering team) Production Superint tendent - Pelletising and Kiln section, Chrome Smelter project. General Superint endent - Metal recovery plant (Construction, Commissioning & Operations) Operations Manager - Two metal recovery plants (Cato Ridge & Krugersdorp) Obtained ISO accreditation, negotiated a five year contract extension, plant upgrade project, increased scope of work. Engineering Manager - Copper beneficiation plant (DMS)

Plant Engineer - Copper beneficiation plant (Floatation)

I would be a positive team player and asset to any Engineering Department. Please contact me on the number given in my CV should there be any questions.

Deon Mike Oberholtzer

Curriculum Vitae

Surname : ■■Oberholtzer
Name : ■■Deon Mike

Date of birth : ■24th September 1970

Id nr : ■■7009245541085
Passport nr : ■A01642892

Email : ■■deon.o@hotmail.co.za Home address: ■20 Villiers Dr

Clarendon

■■■Pietermaritzburg

■■■3201

■■■South Africa

Gender : ■■Male

Marital status : ■Married
Nationality : ■South African
Drivers license : ■Code A & EB

Health :■■Excellent

Educational qualifications

School attended : Christian Brothers College

Bulawayo Zimbabwe

Std. Passed :■■0-Level
Subjects : ■■Mathematics

■■■Science
■■■Geography
■■■Biology
■■■Metal work
■■■English
Year : ■■■1988

Employment history

Name of company : ■■ENRC

Duties: ■Management of the Copper processing plant, engineering department (Superintendents, Foreman +156 employees)

Crushing - 2000T/hr, 54-75 Metso Gyratory crusher, feeders and conveyors.

Milling and Floatation - 1300T/hr, SAG and Ball Mills, screens, secondary crushing circuit, pumps, cyclones, conveyors and associated engineering equipment used in mineral beneficiation.

Acting Engineering Manager (relieving as required) - 9 Superintendents + complim ent of 364 employees.

In 19 months our team has broken all previous plant records, achieving zero LTI's, throughputs up to 855 000Ton in a month and plant availability of up to 96.6%

Year :■■■December 2013 - July 2015

Reason for leaving: ■ ■Retrenched - Expat ratios & Cu price.

Name of company : ■■Glencore (Lion Phase 2, Steelpoort & Lydenburg works)

t

Duties: MMMM Manage the engineering function of two submerged ARC furnaces

Year :■■■March 2013 - December 2013

Reason for leaving : ■Accepted Plant Engineer position with ENRC. Expat salary b enefits

Name of company : ■■Scorpion Mineral Processing (SMP)

Position: **EXE**Engineering Manger

Duties: Total responsibility of the Engineering department on the Copper ben eficiation (DMS) plant owned by SEK, Tiger Resources, in the DRC.

Implement and sustain a predictive preventative maintenance management system Draft and implement engineering procedures

Ensure legal compliance, certification of cranes, lifting equipment, licensing e

Ensure 90% availability of plant and vehicles

Ensure compliance to corporate and site policies

Departmental Safety, Health, Quality & Environment management

Analysis and approval of operational and capital expenditure, ensure cost contro l measures

Operational and Capital Budget compilation

Monthly capital and operational expenditure reporting including diesel, water an d electrical usage

Monthly plant availability & utilisation, engineering and project status reporting

Shutdown, servicing scheduling

Equipment / plant breakdown analysis and corrective measures

Vendor selection and supplier communication

Critical spare inventory review and reduction of capital held in stock

Project management, including civil work.

Install and maintain raw water pump stations and pipe line from nearby river and boreholes for plant consumption.

Sub-contractor management

HR management - implement new hourly paid shift roster to reduce overtime, approval of overtime, time sheets, leave, expat rosters, etc)

Vetting and employment of new engineering employees

Engineering Dept. Disciplinary procedural management

Labour management of 45 engineering staff (strategy, direction, guidance, training-Mechanical Forman, Electrical / Instrumentation Forman, Diesel mechanics, Fitters, Electricians, Instrument technicians, Boilermakers, artisan aids and general workers, Drivers and machine operators)

Maintenance and repair on offices and buildings, on-site accommodation camp, facilities, kitchen and mess hall, clinic etc

Equipment and Machinery:

Sandvik CR 800 Hybrid Primary Crusher

Nordberg Secondary Cone Crushers

Conveying equipment

Vibramech screens (various sizes)

Slurry pumps (Warman)

Scrubbers, Cyclones & Spirals

Magnetic separators

Electrical generators (multiple 1200kva units and smaller)

Electrical site distribution, transformers and MCC's

Tata 86 & 46 seater busses, Toyota mini busses, Toyota Land cruisers & prado's, Grove 40Ton rough terrain crane, Bell 220 Versalift, MT 1440 Maniscopic Manitou, Case TX 140-45 Telehandler, CAT 966 Front End Loaders, Samil and Volvo trucks, CAT forklifts, Bobcat / Skid steers.

Year :■■■May 2012 to December 2012

Reason for leaving : \blacksquare Personal

Name of company : ■■Harsco RSA

Position: Project Manger

Duties: Memory Plant in Cato Ridge.

Project Safety, Health & Quality management

Budget compilation Equipment selection Tender adjudication

Responsible and accountable for the Capital expenditure, approval of orders etc

Contractor management

Plan and chair project meeting with all stakeholders, scheduling, prioritising a nd control

Inspect / approve equipment fabrication, installation & commissioning

Report to Managing Director / General Manager Engineering weekly on total project status

Equipment and Machinery replaced or refurbished:

Primary and Secondary Crushing circuit - Crushers, Conveying equipment, Screens, hydraulic circuits, dust suppression, electrical MCC, distribution and control circuits

Metal recovery - Jigs, pumps, cyclones, spirals, thickeners, Filter Press, Scree ning plant, conveying equipment, mechanical and electrical workshop, laboratory.

Year :■■■May 2011 to April 2012

Reason for leaving: Accepted Engineering Manager position with SEK. Expat salar y benefits & implications

Name of company : **Mathematical** RSA

Duties: Management of two Mineral processing metal recovery operations, Safety, Health, Environment and Quality - Cato Ridge Plant ISO 9000, 14001, 1800 1 full accreditation and certification was acquired in two years from zero compliance.

Legal compliance - Draft, train employees and implement check lists, registers, testing and certification of lifting equipment, operator training and licensing Financial Reporting and cost control, compilation of annual and quarterly Operat ional and Capital budgets, weekly and monthly cost reports.

Implementation, create buy-in from subordinates on executive operational strategies

Draft, train employees and implement Standard operating procedures Accident, Incident investigation and corrective measure implementation

Root cause analysis of failures and breakdowns, corrective measure implementation

Process control, plant and machinery availability, utilisation and optimisation Plant and machinery maintenance strategies - standardisation of equipment

Human resources optimisation (recruitment, training, job specifications, bi-annu al / annual performance reviews / yearly performance based increase justificatio n)

Labour budget and time and attendance approval

Management of labour - Direct reports of 2 x Production Superintendents, 1 x Eng ineering Superintendent, 1 x SHEQ Superintendent, 1 x Site Accountant, 1 x Admin istrator. Total headcount of 100 employees.

Client and customer communications, SLA and contract negotiations and management Client Contract Management - integral member actively involved in the negotiatio ns of the team to be awarded a 5 year Contract extension of the existing process ing contract, including extension of scope of work to the contract.

 ${\tt Sub-contractor\ Management\ -\ Management\ of\ SLA\ and\ contractual\ obligations\ from\ s}$ ervice providers on two sites

Project management - Civil, electrical, mechanical project management and contro 1

Feed and tailings dump management

Facilities management -Electrical reticulation, distribution and control.

Service and repair workshop management

Logistics management - stores control - reduce capital value of stock held whils

t ensuring adequate critical spares available, vendor / supplier negotiations wr t consignment stock

Laboratory management - Sample collection, preparation, analysis, reporting and corrective measure implementation to ensure contractual quality specifications m et at all times.

3rd party aggregate for ready mix and sub-base fill sales Invoicing of client and 3rd party sales

Equipment and Machinery:

Load and Haul -■■

CAT 769D Dumper trucks

CAT 120G Graders

Hitachi 520LCR Excavators

CAT 320D excavator

Liugong 888 Front end loaders

CAT 980 Front end loaders

Bell L1806 Front end loaders

Bell B16 & B25 dumpers

Forklifts, Bobcats, Telehandles

Grove rough terrain crane

Primary & Secondary Crushing and Screening -

Kue Ken Jaw Crusher,

Hadfield 24/36 Jaw Crushers and smaller sample preparation units.

Nordberg, Symons 4.25, Osborn Telsmith Cone crushers

Conveying equipment, weightometers and automatic samplers

Osborn & Vibramech vibrating screens and feeders

Hydraulic equipment and circuits

Electrical transformers, MCC distribution and controls

Dust suppression circuits

Tramp iron magnets

Metal Recovery -

Conveying equipment, weightometers, automatic feeders

Screens - Material sizing and dewatering

Cyclones, up to 1220mm diameter

Slurry Pumps % Clean water high pressure pumps

Jigs - underflow density separation

Spirals, Thickeners, Filter Presses

Compressors

Electrical transformers, MCC distribution and controls

Instrumentation equipment and control, variable speed drives, valves, flow meter s, etc

SCADA control systems

Weighbridge and computerised controls & reporting

Year :■■■March 2008 to April 2012

Reason for leaving: Accepted Engineering Manager position with SMP. Expat salar y benefits & implications

Name of company : **Mathematical** Xstrata Alloys

Position: ■■Superintendent - ■ Kiln section

Metals Recovery Plant

Duties: **Man**Commissioning of the Greenfield project "LION SMELTER"

Manage the teams of operations shift workers and supervisors in the reduction Ki ln section.

Manage the fabrication, establishment and commissioning of the Metal Recovery Pl ant (MRP).

Management of the MRP (post commissioning) including operations and maintenance.

Compilation of process and engineering procedures, risk assessments and HAZOPS.

Development and training of Coordinators and Operators

Budget control & reporting

Ensure compliance to all legislative requirements pertaining to Health, Safety, Environment and Quality Standards.

Plant and process improvement, optimisation of plant and machinery.

Equipment and Machinery:

Kilns

Primary & Secondary Crushing and Screening -

Hadfield 24/36 Jaw Crushers and smaller sample preparation units.

Nordberg, Symons 4.25, Osborn Telsmith Cone crushers

Conveying equipment, weightometers

Osborn & Vibramech vibrating screens and feeders

Hydraulic equipment and circuits

Electrical transformers, MCC distribution and controls

Dust suppression circuits

Tramp iron magnets

Metal Recovery -

Conveying equipment, weightometers, automatic feeders

Screens - Material sizing and dewatering

Cyclones, up to 1220mm diameter

Slurry Pumps & Clean water high pressure pumps

Jigs - underflow density separation

Spirals, Thickeners

Electrical transformers, MCC distribution and controls

Instrumentation equipment and control, variable speed drives, valves, flow meter s, etc

SCADA control systems

Year :■■■August 2005 to February 2008

Reason for leaving: Accepted position with Harsco as Operations Manager. Promot ion

Name of company : ■■SA Ferrochrome and Mining

zing Plant

Duties: Management of the Pelletizing Plant c onsisting of an Engineering section with 15 employees and a Production section of 24 employees. Raw material and final product stock control

Maintenance planning and shut downs

Small project implementation

Sub-contractor supervision and control

Development, implementation and training of subordinates on all SHEQ & operation al related procedures

Accident and incident investigations

Plant machinery and equipment optimisation

Equipment and Machinery:

Material Silos

Pan feeders

Conveying equipment

Ball Mills and grinding media feed circuits

Pelletising Drums

Hydraulic sizing roller screen

Dryers using pulverised coal, Heavy oil fuel & LPG

Outokumpu oxidising grate and kiln

Large suction and positive pressure fans

Cooling towers

Screens

Year :■■■March 2002 to July 2005

Reason for leaving : Accepted position with Xstrata Alloys as Superintendent, pr

omotion

Name of company : **MI**Ferro Metals Ltd

Position:

Maintenance Specialist / Fitter and Turner

Duties: Duties: Coordinating, controlling and implementation of projects at the Pell

etizing and Sinter Plants.

Root cause analysis of all failures and breakdowns

Risk assessment of all contractor tasks and activities

Works permit issuing

Safety, Health, Environment and Quality standards.

Prior to this position I was a Fitter and Turner responsible for maintenance and repairs of equipment including hydraulics, conveyors, drives, crushers, compres sors, pumps, gearboxes, screens, train truck loading and off loading (tipplers)

Year :■■■May 1996 to February 2002

Reason for leaving: Accepted position of Coordinator with SA Ferrochrome and Mining, promotion

Name of company: Improve Coal Corporation - Douglas Colliery
Position: Improve Turner: Underground Operations

Duties: Maintenance on all underground coal mining equipment and machinery on shifts.

I acted as Charge hand for extended periods where I was responsible for planning of maintenance, scheduling of work and management of subordinate employees.

Equipment and Machinery:

Conveying equipment, pumps, screens

Joy and Voest Alpine continuous miners

Scuttle cars, roof bolters, Eimco face shovels, drill rigs, feeder breakers Hydraulics and pneumatics

Year :■■■January 1992 to April 1996

Reason for leaving: Accepted position at Ferro Metals working day shifts only to enable me to continue my studies in mechanical engineering comprising of night classes at the technical college

Courses attended and Certificates achieved :

National Higher Diploma - Mechanical Engineering

■Control Systems■■N6

■Electrotechnics■■■N4*, N5

■Engineering Science■■N4

■Fluid Mechanics■■■N5*, N6*

■Industrial electronics■■N4*, N5

■Mathematics■■■N4

■Mechanotechnics■■N4*, N5*, N6*

■Power Machines■■N5, N6

■Strengths of materials and structures■N5, N6*

■Supervisory Management■N4, N5, N6

*Indicates Distinction

Qualified Fitter and Turner (Red seal)

Basic principles of operations on a pelletizing and sintering plant _ Outokumpu, Finland

MDP - Management Development Program

SDP - Supervisors Development Program

Project Success Tool kit

Multi-Skilled Boilermaker, Welder training

Maintenance of Flame proof equipment
Fire fighting
First Aid level 3
Underground gasses and gas testing
Pragma on-key
SAP
JDE
Microsoft Office - Word, Excel, Power point, Projects, advanced level